Dear Hiring Manager,

I bring over 6 years of experience designing and developing innovative software applications through modern methodologies, effective design patterns and algorithms. My expertise includes back-end and handling cloud infrastructure and services, including requirement analysis, technical specification design, development, implementation, testing, and maintenance.

I am currently working with Accenture Solutions Pvt. Ltd for one of the clients who is trying to gather insight from different Software Project management tools like JIRA, AHA, GITHUB, etc to be used by the executives. Here, my role is to work as a team lead(offshore) under the supervision of Principal Data architect(onshore) and create a flow for the data from the point of origin i.e different tools listed above and make it available for the Visualization team in the required/standard format for offline reporting. I have experience working in multiple domains like healthcare, retail, payment gateway and automobile during my professional career.

Example of my abilities:

- Modern and robust web application development.
- Robust back-end codes and data model design/development/testing.
- Managing Cloud Services.
- Code optimization and review.
- Task management and mentoring subordinates in team.
- Exposure to the ML and AI tech-stack.
- Building RAG solutions and LLM based applications.

My expertise would augment your development team as team lead or selforganized SSE, as I look forward to demonstrating in a personal interview.

Looking forward to hearing from you

Sincerely,

Prason Ghimire

PRASON GHIMIRE





meet.prasonghimire@gmail.com





SKILLS

Application Engineering

- Python/Flask/Fast-API
- Java/Spring/Spring-Boot
- Hibernate/JPA/SQLAlchemy
- Java-script/Oracle-Apex/PowerApps

Database Management

SQL/No-SQL

Cloud Services

Azure / GCP / AWS

Application Deployment

 Docker/Bitbucket (CI-CD) pipelines/Azure DevOps/Kubernetes

Data Analytics and Machine Learning

- Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA)/Predictive modeling
- OpenAI service
- Pandas/NumPy/Matplotlib/Se aborn

Project and Source code Mgmt.

IIRA/GIT/ Bit-bucket /SVN

Miscellaneous

 Linux OS, Elastic Search, Solr, RabbitMQ, MS-Graph-API, JMeter Redis,NIFI,HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

EDUCATION

(2022-2024)(result awaiting)

- Master of Science Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence
 - Liverpool John Mores University,UK

(2014-2018)

- Bachelors in Information Management
 - Tribhuwan University, Kathmandu, Nepal

CERTIFICATIONS / AWARDS

- AZ-900(Azure Fundamentals)
- AI-900(Azure AI Fundamentals)
- SAFe Agile Certification
- Business Communication
- Tenacious Techno/Star Award (Accenture AI Hub)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Involved in Voluntary consulting especially in the Back-end Engineering.
- Involved as a Project coordinator at "Nobel College, Kathmandu" to mentor BCIS(Bachelor-level) students on completing their final-year projects built on Java/RDBMS/Python Stack for 2 years.

SUMMARY

Enthusiast Learner and Problem-Solver in Back-end Engineering, with 6+ years of experience. Worked Primarily on scalable product design/development, technology selection and planning. Delivered some change initiatives to automate the monotonous task for self/colleagues at work. Team player who has also lead 2 direct reportee. Got few nick-name as "Bug-master" and "magic-man" from colleagues after being able to solve long-time opened and escalated issues in short time than anticipated.

EXPERIENCE

Al Engineering Assoc. Manager, Accenture Solutions Pvt. Ltd, Bangalore (June 2022 - Current)

- Working as team lead, ensuring on time-delivery and knowledge sharing practices.
- Involvement in n-tier enterprise application design and development through SDLC process following Agile methodology.
- Expertise in the Back-end services development and EDA (Exploratory Data Analysis) using Python/Pandas/NumPy/Matplotlib.
- Designing workflow and data models for new App/enhancement.
- Generated the Starter-Pack generic build to be used across teams for application development with some prebuilt functionality like login, session-management, CRUD test-case using FAST and FLASK.
- Coordinated with the clients/stakeholders over call/email for requirements gathering and POC approval.
- Improved Security and reducing cost for services running on cloud and resolving deployments and cloud related issues (AWS/GCP/Azure/Azure Devops).
- Researched on solutions feasibility and suggested alternative approach for client/business requirements.
- Restructured and simplified the long running jobs into more manageable and optimized modules.
- Collaborated with departments to discuss technical issues, software system design and maintenance.
- Working with LLM by training on custom data for intelligent chatbot using Azure OpenAI.
- Integrated and Published forms using PowerApps in the Power-Bi dashboards.
- Redesigned the Deployment architecture and refactored REST API ensuring high availability (100% up-time) for application crashing due to increased user load.

Senior Analytics consultant, Bridgei2i Analytics Solutions Pvt. Ltd, (May 2020 - June 2022)

- Joined as Analytics Consultant.
- Developed micro-services for layout Mapping, validation and processing module on python (Flask+ SQLAlchemy), creating file backup in GCP/Azure Storage.
- Deployed projects using Docker(Containerization) technology/Bit-bucket(CI/CD) pipelines/Azure DevOps.
- Integrated AzureAD/Okta/SSO login and third party APIs like Power Bi/JIRA REST API (Flask).
- Built the highly customizable and scalable Data-Pipeline for migrating data from different sources to a common Storage which can be triggered in standalone or clustered execution mode.

Software Engineer, Cotiviti Nepal Pvt. Ltd, Kathmandu, Nepal (June 2018 - April 2020)

- Promoted to Assoc. Software Engineer after 3 months as Trainee.
- Developed and deployed an automation module for data profiling, data cleaning-auditing and email notification using Java and Python.
- Designed, Built and Executed ETL processing for client data on standard as well as nonstandard layouts.
- Built and deployed Task monitoring module in J2EE(Java Enterprise Edition) and PL/SQL scripts.
- Web Application developed and deployed using Oracle Apex.
- Assisting team member in fixing UI related issues on ReactJS/Angular.
- Optimized the DB query, applied additional Indexing and hints to boost the performance of client facing app as well as the PL/SQL packages execution.
- Participated in "Hacka-fest" event organized by Cotiviti to work with Oracle to PostgreSQL data migration. using (java and ORM framework).